A Guide to the Town of Leesburg Municipal Government Center Hanno Weber and Associates Records, 1985-1997, n.d.
Thomas Balch Library
Thomas Balch Library
Town of Leesburg Municipal Government Center Hanno Weber and Associates Records, 1985-1997, n.d.
Thomas Balch Library
M 0214, VC 0083, ART 0012, OMB 029
18 cubic feet.
The collection records Hanno Weber and Associates work as architect, designer, and construction project manager of the Town of Leesburg Municipal Government Center. Included are documents such as correspondence, contracts, invoices, and reports; architectural drawings and sketches; photographs; and material samples.
Hanno Weber and Associates
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection open for research.
Acquisition Information
Hanno Weber and Associates, Chicago, Illinois.
Accruals
2016.0090
Historical Information
Hanno Weber (born 24 September 1937) is an American architect based in Chicago, Illinois. A graduate of Princeton University, he founded Hanno Weber and Associates (HWA) in 1984. The firm specializes in architecture, interior design, site planning, and urban design.
In 1986, after undertaking an analysis of existing government facilities and downtown parking demand, the Town of Leesburg issued a call for designs for a municipal government center and parking complex. The new combined office building and parking complex would consolidate and expand town services as well as alleviate parking shortages, while blending with the historic scale and context of downtown Leesburg. Over 200 architects submitted entries to the competition. Hanno Weber and Associates' design was awarded the first prize of $10,000 and the design commission. The firm also designed the interior of the building, including furnishings and accessories, and served as project manager for construction of the facility. Construction on the municipal government center began in 1988 and was completed in 1991.
Hanno Weber and Associates' design for the municipal government center won several awards, including Architecture and Urban Design Competition, First Award (1987); AIA Urban Design Award of Excellence (1992); and AIA Chicago Chapter Interior Design Certificate of Merit (1992).
Scope and Content
The collection records Hanno Weber and Associates work as architect, designer, and construction project manager of the Town of Leesburg Municipal Government Center. Included are documents such as correspondence, contracts, invoices, and reports; architectural drawings and sketches; photographs; and material samples.
The collection documents all phases of Hanno Weber and Associates work on the project including the initial design and contest submission; project management and programming; relationships with the Town of Leesburg, subcontractors and consultants; the bidding process; construction itself; dedication of the facility; and HWA's promotion of its work. Whenever possible, materials have been arranged in the order outlined in HWA's Project Index (See M 0124, Box 1, Folder 7) as follows: Project Management and Programming; Client Records; Agencies Records; Consultant Records; Bidding; Contractors Records; Contract Accounting; and Construction Administration. Materials relating to the design competition have been placed at the beginning of the collection, and materials relating to publicity subsequent to the completion of the project have been placed at the end of the collection.
Design competition materials include the design manual and guidelines, Leesburg town plan, HWA's winning entry, and the competition results.
The Project Management and Programming section contains materials documenting management of the construction process. These include meetings of minutes with Town of Leesburg officials, design studies and reports, environmental reports, budgets, schedules, photographs of office interiors (see VC 0083), and product information. This section also contains a large number of architectural drawings, including design sketches, working drawings, and alternate plans. For storage reasons, the majority of these drawings are housed in OMB 029. Please see the Drawings Index for a detailed list of drawings.
The Client Records section contains contracts, correspondence, telephone memoranda, and invoices related to HWA's client, the Town of Leesburg.
The Agencies Records section contains materials related to zoning and building permits.
The Consultant Records section contains contracts, correspondence, and invoices relating to various consultants, including mechanical, electrical, and civil engineers.
The Bidding section contains correspondence, evaluations, and other documents relating to the bidding process for the hiring of a construction general contractor.
The Contractor Records section contains correspondence between the general contractor and HWA, as well as Requests for Information (RFI). In addition, this section contains a large number of architectural shop drawings, samples, and related correspondence. The drawings and samples were submitted for HWA's approval by various subcontractors. HWA assigned a number to each submittal, and HWA's index is available ("Submittals Checklist" M 0124, Box 8, Folder 13 and OMB 029, Box 1, Folder 18). The shop drawings contain numerous notes, comments, and corrections. They are stored folded. The shop drawings and samples have been separated from the related correspondence due to their size and preservation storage needs (See M 0124, Box 20-22 and ART 012).
The Contract Accounting section contains Supplemental Instructions, Requests for Change Orders, Certificates of Payment, and other documents.
The Construction Administration section contains Construction Observation reports by HWA, Town of Leesburg, and an outside contractor, as well as minutes of construction meetings, reports, and punch lists. In addition, this section contains photographs taken by both HWA and professional photographers documenting the construction progress (See VC 0083).
The collection also contains materials, including photographs, related to the municipal government center's dedication ceremony held in March 1991. In addition, there are photographs and slides of the completed exterior and interior of the building and correspondence with vendors and architecture and design publications.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bibliography
Hanno Weber and Associates, www.hannoweber.com, accessed 17 March 2017.
Town of Leesburg Municipal Government Center Hanno Weber and Associates Records (M 124), Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA.
Related Material
Town of Leesburg, Virginia Records, 1813-present, Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA
Leesburg Architectural Surveys 1971-2001 (M 016), Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA. Town of Leesburg: Department of Planning, Zoning and Development: (RG 22), Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA. Town of Leesburg: Department of Planning, Zoning and Development: Visual Records of Historic Sites (VC RG 22), Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA
Historical Postcards, 1900-2008 (VC 0004), Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA
Leesburg Opera House Handbill (SC 0012) Thomas Balch Library Leesburg, VA
Contents List
    - Design Competition-"Meeting the Challenge: A Proposal for a Downtown Municipal Government Center-Parking Complex,", 5 May 1986
    - Design Competition-Town Plan, 1986
    - Design Competition-Design Manual, 1987
    - Design Competition-Design Guidelines and Additional Information, 1987
    - Design Competition-Hanno Weber and Associates Drawings, 1987
    - Design Competition-"1987 Design Competition Catalogue,"
    - Project Management and Programming-Project Index, 14 August 1987
    - Project Management and Programming-Project Meeting Minutes, 1987-1989
    - Project Management and Programming-Project Memorandum, 1987-1990
    - Project Management and Programming-Project Budgeting and Estimate, 1987-1989
    - Project Management and Programming-Cost Estimate, 15 December 1987
    - Project Management and Programming-Cost Estimate, 6 June 1988
    - Project Management and Programming-Cost Estimate, 23 June 1988
    - Project Management and Programming-Cost Estimate, 5 December 1988
    - Project Management and Programming-Project Programming, 1987-1989
    - Project Management and Programming-Project Scheduling, 1987
    - Project Management and Programming-Plat of Survey and Topography, 1988
    - Project Management and Programming-Survey Review, 1989
    - Project Management and Programming-Soil Borings and Reports, 1987-1990
    - Project Management and Programming-Area Calculations, 1987-1988
    - Project Management and Programming-Product Information, 1987-1988
    - Project Management and Programming-Lawsuits, 1991-1992
    - Project Management and Programming-Leesburg Demolition, 1985-1990
    - Project Management and Programming-Structural Engineering, 1988
    - Project Management and Programming-Mechanical, Electrical, Plumbing, 1988
    - Project Management and Programming-Task and Drawing List, 1988
    - Project Management and Programming-Drawings and Sketches
    - Project Management and Programming-Working Design Sketch (WDSK) (1 of 2), 1989-1990
    - Project Management and Programming-Working Design Sketch (WDSK) (2 of 2), 1989-1990
    - Project Management and Programming-Other Sketches (1 of 3)
    - Project Management and Programming-Other Sketches (2 of 3)
    - Project Management and Programming-Other Sketches (3 of 3)
    - Project Management and Programming-Parking Area, 1988
    - Project Management and Programming-Interiors-Preliminary Furnishings, 1987, n.d.
    - Project Management and Programming-Interiors-Space Planning, 1987-1988
    - Project Management and Programming-Interiors-Schedule, 1988
    - Project Management and Programming-Interiors-Furnishings Pricing, 1988-1991
    - Project Management and Programming-Interiors-Furnishings Pricing
    - Project Management and Programming-Interiors-Furnishings Proposals, 1987-1989, n.d.
    - Project Management and Programming-Interiors-Product Catalogs, 1988, n.d.
    - Project Management and Programming-Interiors-Equipment, 1988, n.d.
    - Project Management and Programming-Interiors-Drawings and Sketches
    - Project Management and Programming-Interiors-Furnishings Sketches, 1989, n.d.
    - Client Records-Contract, 1987-1988
    - Client Records-Correspondence, July 1987-December 1987
    - Client Records-Correspondence, January 1988-May 1988
    - Client Records-Correspondence, June 1988-September 1988
    - Client Records-Correspondence, October 1988-December 1988
    - Client Records-Correspondence, January 1989-July 1989
    - Client Records-Correspondence, August 1989-November 1989
    - Client Records-Correspondence, December 1989-April 1990
    - Client Records-Correspondence, May 1990-August 1990
    - Client Records-Correspondence, September 1990-June 1991
    - Client Records-Correspondence, July 1991-December 1991
    - Client Records-Correspondence, 1992-1994
    - Client Records-Correspondence with T.J. Rio (Carroll County, MD), 1990
    - Client Records-Telephone Memoranda, 1987-1993
    - Client Records-Billing, 1987-1988
    - Client Records-Billing, 1989-1990
    - Client Records-Billing, 1991-1993
    - Agencies Records-Code and Zoning Analysis, 1988-1990
    - Agencies Records-Zoning Ordinance, 1989
    - Agencies Records-American National Standards Institute Correspondence, 1988
    - Agencies Records-Subsurface Exploration and Settlement Study, 14 August 1990
    - Agencies Records-Building Permits, 1989-1991
    - Consultant Records-Structural Engineer Contract and Invoices, October 1988-December 1988
    - Consultant Records-Structural Engineer Correspondence, 1987-1988
    - Consultant Records-Structural Engineer Correspondence, 1989-1992
    - Consultant Records- Mechanical Engineer Contract and Invoices, 1987-1992
    - Consultant Records-Mechanical Engineer Correspondence, 1988-1990
    - Consultant Records-Mechanical Engineer Correspondence, 1991-1993
    - Consultant Records-Electrical Engineer Correspondence, 1987-1990
    - Consultant Records-Civil Engineer Contract and Invoices, 1987-1991
    - Consultant Records-Civil Engineer Correspondence, 1987-1989
    - Consultant Records-Civil Engineer Correspondence, 1990-1991
    - Consultant Records-Acoustics, 1988
    - Consultant Records-Lighting Design, 1988
    - Consultant Records-MEP, 1988
    - Bidding-Purchasing Policy, 1987-1989
    - Bidding-Instructions to Bidders for Procurement Contracts, n.d.
    - Bidding-Revisions to Contract Documents, 1989
    - Bidding-Correspondence, 1987-1992
    - Bidding-Bidder Questions, 1989
    - Bidding-General Contractors List, 1988-1989
    - Bidding-Substitutions, 1989
    - Bidding-Interior Bidders, 1989-1990
    - Bidding-Furnishing Bidders, 1989
    - Contractor Records-General Contractor Contract and Related Documents-General Contractor, 1989
    - Contractor Records-General Contractor-Construction Manager Correspondence, 1989
    - Contractor Records-General Contractor-Construction Manager Correspondence, 1990
    - Contractor Records-General Contractor-Construction Manager Correspondence, 1991-1993
    - Contractor Records-Request for Information Log, 1989-1991
    - Contractor Records-Requests for Information (RFI 1-51), May 1989-July 1989
    - Contractor Records-Requests for Information (RFI 1-51), August 1989-August 1992
    - Contractor Records-Requests for Information (RFI 51-100), October 1989-January 1990
    - Contractor Records-Requests for Information (RFI 51-100), February 1990-April 1990
    - Contractor Records-Requests for Information (RFI 101-150), April 1990-September 1990
    - Contractor Records-Requests for Information (RFI 101-150), September 1990-December 1990
    - Contractor Records-Requests for Information (RFI 151-180), 1990-1991
    - Contractor Records-Contractor Records-General Contractor Telephone Communication, 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Furnishings Contractor Correspondence, 1990
    - Contractor Records-Furnishings Contract, 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Millwork Contractor Correspondence, 1990
    - Contractor Records-Millwork Contract, 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Other Contractors, 1989-1992
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-Shop Drawing and Sample Record Sheet, 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-Submittals Checklist, 1989-1992
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-Leesburg Survey, 1988
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-2.2 Excavation, 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-2.4 Pavers, 1990-1991
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-2.5 Bituminous Paving, 1991
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-2.56 Granular Paving, 1991
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-2.65 Exterior Sewer System, 1991
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-2.7 Irrigation, 1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-2.8 Site Furnishings, 1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-2.9 Sod and Topsoil, 1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-2.95 Planting, 1991
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-3.1 Concrete Admixtures, 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-3.15 Structural Precast Concrete, 1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-3.15 Structural Precast Concrete, 1990-1991
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-3.2 Architectural Precast Concrete (1 of 3), 1989
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-3.2 Architectural Precast Concrete (2 of 3), 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-3.2 Architectural Precast Concrete (3 of 3), 1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-3.65 Gypsum Concrete, 1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-4.1 Unit Masonry, 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-5.1 Steel, 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-5.2 Miscellaneous Metals, 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-5.2 [sic] Steel Stairs, 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-5.3 Metal Decking, 1989
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-5.4 Light Gauge Framing, 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-5.8 Expansion Joints, 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-6.1 Rough Carpentry, 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-6.3 Millwork, 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-7.1 Foundation Damp Proofing and Waterproofing, 1989
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-7.15 Fluid Applied Protective Membrane Waterproofing, 1989
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-7.2 Plastic Insulation, 1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-7.22 Mineral Insulation, 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-7.25 Fireproofing, 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-7.5 Protective Membrane Roofing Assembly, 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-7.6 Metal Roofing and Siding, 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-7.72 Roof Accessories, 1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-7.8 Metal Framed Skylights, 1989-1991
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-7.82 Unit Skylight, 1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-7.9 Sealant, 1990-1991
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-8.1 Hollow Metal Doors and Frames, 1989-1991
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-8.2 Wood Doors, 1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-8.3 Access Doors, 1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-8.6 Aluminum Clad Wood Windows, 1989
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-8.7 Finish Hardware, 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-8.8 Glass and Glazing, 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-8.9 Aluminum Doors, 1990-1992
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-9.0 Cork Board, 1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-9.25 Interior Gypsum Board Construction, 1989-1991
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-9.3 Ceramic Tile, 1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-9.5 Acoustical Ceiling, 1990-1991
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-9.65 Resilient Flooring, 1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-9.68 Broadloom Carpet, 1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-9.83 Elastomeric Decking Coating, 1989-1991
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-9.98 Fabric Wall Coverings, 1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-9.9 Painting, 1990-1991
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-10.1 Directions/Display Cases, 1990-1991
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-10.15 Toilet Partitions, 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-10.2 Aluminum Louvers, 1989-1991
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-10.35 Flag Poles, 1989
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-10.4 Architectural Signage, 1989-1991
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-10.5 Lockers, 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-10.52 Fire Protection Cabinets, 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-10.8 Toilet and Bath accessories, 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-11.13 Projection Screens, 1989
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-11.15 Parking Controls, 1990-1991
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-11.16 Dock Bumpers, 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-11.46 Kitchen Equipment, 1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-12.51 Louver Blinds, 1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-12.68 Foot Grilles, 1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-13.04 Cashier Booths, 1990-1991
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-14.1 Elevator Layout, 1989-1991
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-14.3 Elevator Cab, 1989-1991
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-15.4 Plumbing (1 of 2), 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-15.4 Plumbing (2 of 2), 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-15.5 Fire Protection, 1989-1991
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-15.7-8-9 HVAC (1 of 2), 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-15.7-8-9 HVAC (2 of 2), 1989-1990
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-16 HVAC (1 of 4), 1989-1991
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-16 HVAC (2 of 4), 1989-1991
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-16 HVAC (3 of 4), 1989-1991
    - Contractor Records-Architectural Shop Drawings and Samples-16 HVAC (4 of 4), 1989-1991
    - Contractor Records-Interior Shop Drawings and Samples-Samples and Cut Sheets, 1990
    - Contractor Records-Interior Shop Drawings and Samples-Accessories, 1990-1992
    - Contractor Records-Interior Shop Drawings and Samples-Millwork Furnishings Maintenance Instructions, 1990
    - Contractor Records-Interior Shop Drawings and Samples-12.2 Hardware, 1990
    - Contractor Records-Interior Shop Drawings and Samples-12.2 Millwork Samples, 1990
    - Contractor Records-Interior Shop Drawings and Samples-12.2 Millwork Drawings, 1990
    - Contractor Records-Interior Shop Drawings and Samples-Color and Material Samples, 1988-1989, n.d.
    - Contractor Records-Interior Shop Drawings and Samples-Furnishings Samples, 1990
    - Contract Accounting-Supplemental Instructions, 1989-1990
    - Contract Accounting-Supplemental Instructions-General Furnishings, 1990
    - Contract Accounting-Supplemental Instructions-Millwork Furnishings, 1989-1991
    - Contract Accounting-Requests for Change Order, 1989-1991
    - Contract Accounting-Request for Change Order Correspondence, June 1989-October 1989
    - Contract Accounting-Request for Change Order Correspondence, November 1989-July 1990
    - Contract Accounting-Request for Change Order Correspondence, August 1990-January 1991
    - Contract Accounting-Request for Change Order Correspondence, February 1991-May 1991
    - Contract Accounting-Request for Change Order Correspondence, June 1991-July 1991
    - Contract Accounting-Request for Change Order Correspondence, August 1991-1993
    - Contract Accounting-Executed Change Orders, 1989-1993
    - Contract Accounting-Requests for Change Order-Furnishings, 1990-1991
    - Contract Accounting-Requests for Change Order-Millwork, 1990-1991
    - Contract Accounting-Time Extension Reports, 1989-1991